[SPEAKER_00] Next time you watch the news, notice how the anchors exaggerate their mouth movement.
[SPEAKER_00] There's a good reason for this. Their job is to speak as clearly as possible.
[SPEAKER_00] And I'll show you a simple drill to help you do that too. All you need is a pen.
[SPEAKER_00] Practicing this quick drill regularly will train you to be more articulate with little effort.
[SPEAKER_00] Place a pen between your teeth and read a paragraph from a book out loud,
[SPEAKER_00] focusing on pronouncing each sound clearly. Then read it again without the pen.
[SPEAKER_00] There will be a noticeable improvement in your enunciation.
[SPEAKER_00] Clearly articulating your words avoids the risk of miscommunication and lost engagement,
[SPEAKER_00] and it makes it easy and pleasurable to listen to you.
[SPEAKER_00] Do this regularly, and you'll reap the benefits.